<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V1.1//EN" "document-v11.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>Quick Start</title>
    <authors><person email="" name="Christian Geisert"/></authors>
  </header>
  <body>
    <p>
    <code>java -jar tn5250j.jar</code></p>
    <p>
    On first invocation of the emulator there where be some warning messages
    that will be output to the console.  These are to inform you that defaults
    files are being setup for you for first run.</p>
    <p>
    You will be presented with a Connections screen for defining sessions.
    Select the configure button to define sessions when the session selection
    window is displayed.</p>
    <p>or</p>
    <p><code>java -jar tn5250j.jar host -p port</code></p>
    <p>or</p>
    <p><code>java -jar tn5250j.jar host</code></p>
    <section><title>Command line options(If you do not want to use the configure button)</title>
    <source>
    -p port ----> port to be used - default is port 23 if not specified

    -f filename ----> configuration file.  This is defined on the Session
                      Configuration screen under Options Tab - Configuration
                      File Name.

    -t ----> use system name instead of system id Host IP Address/DNS Host name.

    -cp ---> Code Page
                Supported code pages
                --------------------
                37 - US default
                37PT - Portuguese
                273 - German
                280 - Italian
                284 - Spanish
                297 - French
                500-ch - Switzerland
                870-pl - Poland

                Let me know of others that are needed.  The code pages can be
                updated quickly.

    -e ----> Enhanced 5250 option.  This gives graphical windows, edit masked
               fields, continued edit fields, etc...
               ** Note ** not all enhanced options are implemented as yet.
               I have only implemented what our applications use here and should
               be considered as improving (buggy :-)).  At our site we have not
               had any problems with it yet (note the word yet please).
               Watch for further announcements and improvements.

    -L ----> Specify the locale/language to be used for literals.  The default
               is the locale of the system if it is supported.

                  Available Languages
                     Default -> Supported locale of the system or English
                     Spanish -> -L es
                     German -> -L de
                     French  -> -L fr
                     Portuguese -> -L pt
                     Catalan -> -L ca_ES
                     Dutch -> -L nl
                     Italian -> -L it
                     Polish -> -L pl

    -132 ----> Change to 27*132 column.

    -s ------> Start up emulator using an existing configured session
                  you can specify multiple of these as in -s xxxx -s yyyy
                  and at startup the emulator will start up session xxxx and
                  yyyy.  This does not use the sessions file but the entries
                  that are defined inside for PRE-EXISTIING session
                  definitions.

                  format of the session entries:
                  ------------------------------

                  systemName=route-to-host [options as described above]

                  The parameter is used along the systemName entry that
                  is passed on the command line.  Please see examples
                  below.

               ==========================================================
               **** NOTE **** Session names are case sensitive!!!!!!!
               =========================================================

    -width --> Start up emulator using the width specified

    -height -> Start up emulator using the height specified

    -d ------> if no other instances are running and the -nc options is not
               specified then start up the bootstrap monitoring thread

    -nc -----> no check for other tn5250j instances that are running
                    A new frame will be created within another instance
                    of JVM

    -noembed-> Do not add a new session tab but open in new frame.  Default
               is embed so add a new session tab in the visible frame.

    -usp ----> Use Socks Proxy
    -sph ----> Socks Proxy Host - please read step 10 below.
               I do believe that you can set the user name and password to be
               used by supplying the following on the the command line to start
               the emulator.
               -Djava.net.socks.username="username" &lt;- replace user name with yours
               -Djava.net.socks.password="password" &lt;- replace password with yours

               Example command line:
               =====================
               java -Djava.net.socks.username="kjp1" -Djava.net.socks.password="tn5250j" -jar tn5250j.jar

               I have not tried this so please let me know if it works.

    -spp ----> Socks Proxy Port

    -dn -----> This option takes a device name parameter to be used
               by the Host.  The device name is 10 characters in
               length and following rfc2877 it the device name
               is already allocated then the device name will be
               sent again with a consecutive number appended.  If
               the device name plus appended sequencial number is
               longer than 10 characters then the device name is
               truncated until the device name and the appended
               sequential number fits within 10 characters.

             For example:
             -dn DEVICEUSER

             This will send the device name on allocation to the host
             as DEVICEUSER.  If there is already a session allocated
             with device name DEVICEUSER then the emulator will send
             the device name with a 1 (number one) appended as
             DEVICEUSE1 if this is allocated then DEVICEUSE2 and so
             on until the host says no more attempts are allowed or
             the same device name is sent twice in succession as per
             rfc2877.

             This option will also change the session name to that
             of the allocated device name.

    -MDI ----> Use the MDI interface represented by JInternalFrames instead of
               tabs.
               --------- N O T E ---------
               New feature for now and is in testing.  Please send comments/
               feedback/bugs.
      </source>
    </section>
    <section><title>Example of command line options</title>
    <p>
    <code>java -jar tn5250j.jar -L es</code></p>
    <p>
    This will change the default language of the system to use the languange
    translations of what is specified.</p>
    <p>
    <code>java -jar tn5250j.jar hostAS400 -f hostAS400.prop</code></p>
    <p>
       This will connect to hostAS400 and use the file hostAS400.prop as the
       property file.  Any properties that are changed will be saved to this
       file under the current directory.  It does not have to exist as it will
       be created.  If there are any properties saved from a previous session
       then those will be read and used.  It uses the code page 37 which is
       default.</p>
    <p>
    <code>java -jar tn5250j.jar parisAS400 -f parisAS400.prop -cp 297</code></p>
    <p>
    This will connect to parisAS400 use the property file as described above
    and use the code page 297 for french.</p>
    <p>
    <code>java -jar tn5250j.jar spainAS400 -f spainAS400.prop -cp 284 -e</code></p>
    <p>
        This will connect to spainAS400 use the property file as described above
        and use the code page 284 for spanish and will notify the as400 that it
        can send enhanced commands.</p>
    <note>the -e can be used on all sessions.</note>
    </section>
    <section><title>Format of the session entries</title>
    <source>
systemName=route-to-host [options as described above]
    </source>
    </section>
    <section><title>Sample sessions file</title>
    <source>
luxembourg=lux -f luxgui.prop -e -gui
lux-nogui=lux -f lux.prop -e
houilles=houilles -f houilles.prop -cp 297 -e
paris=paris -f paris.prop -cp 297 -e
spain=spain -f spain.prop -cp 284 -e
</source>
<note>Session names are case sensitive!!!!!!!</note>
</section>
<section><title>Example of command line option -s</title>

    <p>
    Command line usage follows:
    </p>
    <source>
java -jar tn5250j.jar -s luxembourg
    </source>
    <p>
    This will search the session file for the entry luxembourg and if found
    use the the entry parameters that are defined for that session.
    </p>
    <p>
    So using the Sample sessions file described above the program would read
    the -s option and obtain luxembourg.  It would then search the sessions
    file for this entry and if found execute the options that where there:
    </p>
    <p>
    system/ip addrss = lux
    configuration file = luxgui.prop
    -e = use enhanced mode
    -gui = start in gui mode
    </p>
    <p>
    If an entry is not found for the -s option then the Connection dialog
    is displayed for you to enter a new connection or select a pre existing
    one from the list.
    </p>

</section>

<section><title>Configure a 5250 Display Session</title>

    <p>
    <strong>Step 1 - Start the emulator as described above</strong>
    </p>
    <p>
    You will then be presented with the following screen
    </p>
    <figure alt="" src="images/connect1.png"/>

    <p>
    <strong>Step 2 - Click the Add button</strong>
    </p>
    <p>
    This will allow you to define a new session and it's options to be used
    within the emulator.
    </p>
    <figure alt="" src="images/connect2.png" />

    <p>
    <strong>Step 3 - Specify a name for the session</strong>
    </p>
    <p>
    The name supplied here identifies the session.
    </p>
    <figure alt="" src="images/connect3.png" />

    <p>
    <strong>Step 4 - Specify the IP Address</strong>
    </p>
    <ol>
        <li>
        Click the TCP/IP Tab to supply the host address of your AS400
        </li>
        <li>
        Modify the port number if needed.  The normal default is port 23.
        </li>
        <li>
        Specify a device name to connect with if desired.  This is not requred
        </li>
        <li>
        Click Add at the bottom of the dialog box.  This will return you to the
        Connect dialog..
        </li>
    </ol>
    <figure alt="" src="images/connect4.png" />

    <p>
    <strong>Step 5 - Select Connect</strong>
    </p>
    <p>
    From the Connect dialog select your new session with the mouse so that
    it is highlighted and then click Connect or Alt-C.
    </p>
    <figure alt="" src="images/connect5.png" />

    <p>
    <strong>You should now be presented with a sign on screen</strong>
    </p>
    <figure alt="" src="images/connect7.png" />

</section>

  </body>
</document>
