<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V1.1//EN" "document-v11.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>Scripting</title>
  </header>
  <body>

    <p>
This version of the emulator allows scripting using the python language.  This
is accomplished using the jython library.
    </p>
    <p>
        <jump href="http://www.jython.org/">Jython Home Page</jump>
    </p>

  <section><title>What is it</title>

    <p>
You can interract with the emulator such as:
    </p>
    
    <source>
 screen = _session.getScreen()
 screen.sendKeys("[enter]")

    </source>
    <p>
 to send keystrokes.
    </p>

    <p>
 ----------------------------
 Popup frames and labels:
 ----------------------------
    </p>
    <source>
 win = swing.JFrame("tn5250j test window")
 win.size = (300,400)
 win.contentPane.background = awt.Color.white
 label = swing.JLabel("Hello all you tn5250j'ers script writers")
 label.foreground = awt.Color.red
 win.contentPane.add(label)
 win.show()
    </source>
    <p>
 -------------------
 Access to fields:
 -------------------
    </p>
    <source>
 screen = _session.getScreen()

 screenfields = screen.getScreenFields()

 fields = screenfields.getFields()

 for x in fields:
     print x.toString()
     print x.getText()

 print "number of fields %s " % screenfields.getSize()

    </source>

    <p>
 Now the fun part.  Repetative tasks.  This is really cool as well.
 ------------------------------------------------------------------
    </p>
    <source>
 screen = _session.getScreen()

 while not _session.isStopMacroRequested():
     screen.sendKeys("[pf5]")
     time.sleep(5)
    </source>

    <p>
 Four lines and you have a continuas refresh every 5 seconds until you turn
 it off.
    </p>
    <note>
 The session.isStopMacroRequested() is very important here!!!
    </note>
    <p>
  Is this not the best thing ever.
    </p>
 ---------------------------------------------------------------
    <p>
 All in python.  Very powerful and fun to write.
    </p>

    </section>

  <section><title>Install</title>

    <p>
 1.  go to <jump href="http://sourceforge.net/projects/jython">http://sourceforge.net/projects/jython</jump> and download the latest
 release.
    </p>
    <p>
 2.  install jython.  Follow their directions.  It is very simple
    </p>
    <note>
    Steps one and two are only necessary if you want to have the full jython
    environment.  It is not necessary to install the full package as it is
    distributed with the emulator via CVS or within the tn5250j-x.x.x-bin-scripting.zip
    file in the downloads section.  Go ahead and download it to show them your support.
    You will also be able to test out the functionality of the jython in an interactive
    environment.
    </note>
    <p>
 3.  checkout or update from CVS the tn5250j emulator.
    </p>
    <p>
 4.  move the jython.jar file from where you installed jython and place it in
 your libs directory of the build directory.  This will follow the same
 procedure as for setting up e-mail.  Tip: you do not have to install jython
 on every computer just the jython.jar file.
    </p>
    <p>
 5.  from command line for ant execute the following

 >ant all
    </p>
    <note>
    Step five is for compiling from CVS only.  If you downloaded the bin-scripting.zip
    file then you have all the files necessary.
    </note>
    <p>

 6.  Create a directory underneath called "scripts".  This is hardcoded so
 that all scripts are based off the scripts directory.
    </p>
    <p>
 7.  When everything builds, fire up the emulator making sure the jython.jar
 file is in the directoy, same as for setting up e-mail.
    <note>
    Make sure the jython.jar file is in the same directory you installed the 
    tn5250j.jar.
    </note>
    </p>
    <p>
 8.  Copy the sample scripts to the scripts directory.  Available in the source download.
    </p>
    <p>
 9.  Hit Alt-R to receive a Run Script prompt and type in the full name of
 the script.  Such as testwin.py or testlooping.py
    </p>
    <p>
 10. Or from the popup menu all the scripts in the directory should appear
     in the macros sub menu
    </p>
    <p>
<strong>Enjoy!!!</strong>
    </p>
    </section>

  </body>
</document>
