<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V1.1//EN" "document-v11.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>Applet</title>
  </header>
  <body>
      <p>
      This version of the emulator includes an applet version of the emulator to be
      embedded in a webbrowser.</p>
      <p>
      Big thanks goes to Bob Fludder at http://www.businessvision.au for testing and
      helping with this.  He is suppose to write a how to and/or deployment for the
      applet version of the emulator.</p>
      <note>
      Help is needed here with information and or changes to the code to allow a
      seemless integration.  There are probably bugs in there so please be nice when
      reporting them ;-)</note>
    <section><title>Tested Browsers</title>
    <p>Netscape</p>
    </section>
    <section><title>Tested Plugins</title>
    <ul>
        <li>1.3.1</li>
        <li>1.4 beta 3</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
    One thing about the 1.4 beta 3 plugin is that it allows a signed jar to be
    loaded and the proper authority is prompted for the certificate.  Once accepted
    the certificate is then saved thus saving the deployment, installation and
    importing of keys/signatures to each of the desktops.  Very Very nice.</p>
    </section>
    <section><title>Deployment</title>
    <p>
    There are to applet html files that are included:
    <ul>
        <li><code>My5250App.html</code></li>
        <li><code>My5250AppPlugin.html</code></li>
    </ul>
    </p>
    <p>
    I am going to have to refer you to the experts at the discussion forum of sun
    at the following:
    <link href="http://forum.java.sun.com/thread.jsp?forum=63&amp;thread=174214">
    http://forum.java.sun.com/thread.jsp?forum=63&amp;thread=174214</link></p>
    <p>
    This has the best information on signing and deploying applets.  This being my
    first applet program I am at a lost for help on deployment for the different
    browsers and I do not have the time to test them all.</p>
    <note>
    Help is needed here with information and or changes to the code to allow a
    seemless integration.  There are probably bugs in there so please be nice when
    reporting them ;-)
    </note>
    </section>
    <section><title>Applet Parameters</title>
    <p>
    All command line options are supported for applet parameters except for the
    -f argument for file properties.  Looking for suggestion here!!!!!!!!</p>
    <p>
    If you have any questions or suggestions please let me know.  If you have code
    changes PLEASE PLEASE send them to me.</p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
