<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V1.1//EN" "document-v11.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>Menu Options</title>
  </header>
  <body>
  <p>
Copy - Copies bounded area or if no bounded area selected copies the screen to
         the clipboard to be pasted
  </p>
  <p>Paste - Pastes clipboard data to the screen</p>
  <p>
Paste Special - This will paste the data from the clipboard stripping all non
                  letter and non numeric characters.
</p>
<source>
   Example:
   --------
                                 Display Report
                                              Report width . . . . . :     556
 Position to line  . . . . .              Shift to column  . . . . . .
 Line   ....+....1....+....2....+....3....+....4....+....5....+....6....+....7..
        Opening Branch......  Company Id..........  Application Code....       A
 000001         1,091                00069                   D
 000002         2,010                00069                   D
 000003         2,010                00069                   D
 000004         2,010                00069                   D
 000005         2,010                00069                   D
</source>
   <p>
   The Opening Branch...... field has a comma within the field, if you do just a
   regular copy and paste into a field you would get 1,091 which sometimes is
   not formatted correctly so you would use the paste special and what would be
   pasted is 1091</p>
   <p>
Selected columns and Selected rows - shows the status of the selection.  We use
            this to count the characters of a selection.  Note these two entries
            will only show up if there is a bounded area specified.</p>
<p>
Sum Area1   This option will only show up if there was a bounded area selected
            for example copy and paste.
</p>
<p>
            You can select two different formats to parse numbers.  The Grouping
            separator as ',' and a '.' as Decimal Separator, #,###.## or
            the grouping seaparator as '.' and a ',' as Decimal Separator,
            #.###,##  .
</p>
<p>Print Screen - Prints the screen</p>
<p>System Request - Issues a System Request to the AS400 system</p>
<p>
Help - NOTE this is not application help but the help key that is sent to the
         AS400</p>
<p>
Host Print - This will send a host print to the AS400 which will print the
               screen to the users spool</p>
<p>
Display Messages - Will only display if there are messages waiting (ie. the
                     MW light is on).  When the option is selected the messages
                     will be displayed.  Alt + M will also do this but you can
                     press this at any time.
</p>
<p>Hex Map - Displays a hex map of ASCII characters that can be inserted into the
            current field</p>
<p>
Map Keys - Displays a window to allow remapping of the keys for the emulator</p>
<p>
Settings - Displays a window to allow the changing of the font, colors,
            cursor size and column separator.</p>
<p>
Macros - If there are macros defined then this item will be displayed.  It will
            have a submenu of all macros defined across the sessions.  More
            information can be found in the macros.txt file.</p>
<p>
Transfer file - The user is presented with a screen to fill out the file
                  information to be downloaded.  More information can be
                  found in the filetransfers.txt file.</p>
<p>
Send Screen - Send screen via e-mail.  More information can be
                  found in the e-mail.txt file.</p>
<p>
Connect/Disconnect - This is a toggle switch.  When connected this entry will
            read Disconnect and when disconnected this item will read Connect.</p>
<p>
Close this session - Will popup a options panel that will allow you to close
            the current session or all sessions and remove the sessions from
            the session tab panel.</p>
<p>
Left mouse button held down allows you to specify a bounding area.
</p>
    <note>English Version</note>
    <p>
    Right click on session screen pulls up a menu as follows:</p>
<source>
:=====================:
: Copy                :
: Paste               :
: Paste Special       :
:---------------------:
: Selected Columns XX :
: Selected Rows XX    :
: Sum Area          > :
:---------------------:
: Print Screen        :
:---------------------:
: System Request      :
: Help                :
: Host Print          :
: Display Messages    :
:---------------------:
: Hex Map             :
: Map Keys...         :
: Settings...         :
:---------------------:
: Macros            > :
:---------------------:
: Transfer File...    :
: Send Screen         :
:---------------------:
: Connect/Disconnect  :
: Close this session  :
:=====================:
</source>
  </body>
</document>
