<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE document PUBLIC "-//APACHE//DTD Documentation V1.1//EN" "document-v11.dtd">
<document>
  <header>
    <title>File Transfers</title>
  </header>
  <body>
    <p>
    This version of the emulator will allow the downloading of file information from
    an as400.  It will be formatted as an HTML table with the headers being the
    field names.</p>
    <note>    
    I have only been able to test with with OS/400 V4R5 so if there are any problems
    with offsets of fields please let me know</note>
    <section><title> Modifications for this release 0.4.14 adds</title>
      <ul>
        <li>Selection of decimal separator to use for numbers</li>
        <li>KSpreadSheet file filter</li>
        <li>OpenOffice file filter</li>
      </ul>
      <note>
      for the filters if the numbers do not show up correctly
      try downloading with the other decimal separator.</note>
    </section>
    <section><title>Modifications for this release 0.4.9 adds</title>
      <ul>
        <li>File browser for selecting local file</li>
        <li>Fix for Signed Numeric fields</li>
        <li>Transfer progression panel</li>
        <li>Ouput panel of commands and responses from OS400</li>
        <li>Transfers are executed in threads to keep user interface
        from locking up</li>
        <li>Support for member transfer and size information used for
        transfer progress</li>
        <li>Local file is appended with the correct extension of the output format
        for instance in this release we only support HTML so the file will
        be appended with .html if not specified</li>
        <li>Testing for fields transferred if correct or not.</li>
        <li>Field types tested:</li>
      </ul>
      <source>
     A
     A          R DWNLOAD
     A            FIELD1        10A         COLHDG('Field 1............
     A            FIELD2        10P 0       COLHDG('Field 2............
     A            FIELD3        10P 3       COLHDG('Field 3............
     A            FIELD4        10S 0       COLHDG('Field 4............
     A            FIELD5        10S 3       COLHDG('Field 5............
     A            FIELD6        10B 0       COLHDG('Field 6............
     A            FIELD7        10B 0       COLHDG('Field 7............
     A            FIELD8         5F 0       COLHDG('Field 7............
     A            FIELD9         5F 3       COLHDG('Field 8............
     A            FIELD10         L         COLHDG('Field 9............
     A            FIELD11         T         COLHDG('Field 10...........
     A            FIELD12         Z         COLHDG('Field 11...........
     A            FIELD13        6H         COLHDG('Field 12...........
    </source>
    <note>
    I do not know if I am downloading everything correctly.  Please
    check the files for accuracy and let me know of any problems.</note>
    </section>
    <section><title>Navigating File Transfer Panel</title>
      <p>
      Right click on session screen pulls up a menu as follows:</p>
<source>
:=====================:
: Copy                :
: Paste               :
: Paste Special       :
:---------------------:
: Selected Columns XX :
: Selected Rows XX    :
:---------------------:
: Print Screen        :
:---------------------:
: System Request      :
: Help                :
: Host Print          :
: Display Messages    :
:---------------------:
: Hex Map             :
: Map Keys...         :
: Settings...         :
:---------------------:
: Macros            > :
:---------------------:
: Transfer File...    :
:---------------------:
: Connect/Disconnect  :
:=====================:
</source>
    <p>
    After getting the popup menu you will see an option for Transfer File...  Select
    the menu item and you will be presented with a screen to supply the transfer
    parameters.</p>
    <p>
    The following information is requested.</p>
<source>
System Name - The DNS name or IP address of the system that you want to connect
               download files from

File Name - The host file name that you want to download.  The default root
               directory is probably QGPL so you will have to supply the full
               name of the file in the format of LIBRARY/FILE.MEMBER

User Id - User Id for security signon

Password - Password for the user.

PC File Name - The local file name where the data is to be placed.  The default
                  directory is the path of the emulator.  If you want to place
                  it somewhere else you will need to specify the full path name
                  where to place it.

                  The file is in HTML format so you will probably want to name
                  the file with and extension of .htm or .html

Browse Button - Select button to pull up the file browser

Decimal separator - Select the decimal separator to be used for formatting
                     numbers.
</source>
    <p>
    If you have any questions or suggestions please let me know.</p>
    <p>
    The source code is a mess as usual so I will be adding comments sometime in the
    future as well.</p>
    <p>Enjoy!!!</p>
  </section>
  </body>
</document>
